《黑镜》
《沃多时刻》
他们可以见你了
They're ready for you now
格温多林·哈里斯  我们见过面
Gwendolyn Harris. We've met.
在伯恩茅斯
Bournemouth.
但是其他人你不认识
But you don't know the others.
是  但我对你们很熟悉
No, but I'm familiar with you.
你为什么想成为国会议员呢
Why do you want to be an MP?
因为我对现实不满意
Because I'm not satisfied with the way things are,
相比于坐着抱怨  我更愿做点什么
and rather than sit back and moan I'd prefer to do something about it.
从头再来一遍
Go again from the top.
我不知道为什么会有人
I don't know why anyone's surprised
为世界第一少年偶像成为
the world's number one teen idol
山达基教徒而惊讶
has become a Scientologist.
题词机速度快点
Speed up the autocue, please.
明星总会信一些奇怪的东西
Pop stars do believe in weird things.
阿巴乐队(瑞典乐队)相信天使
Abba believed in angels.
劳·凯利(黑人歌手)相信自己能飞
R Kelly believed he could fly...
他们让你看这个
They said show you this.
这是刚发生的吗
This happened just now?
格莱德维尔
Gladwell?
大标题  保守党杰森·格莱德维尔引咎辞职
"Shamed Tory Jason Gladwell resigns," capitals...
全因推特色情图片丑闻
"Over Twitter porn pics scandal."
那他不是被盗号了
Oh, so he wasn't hacked after all.
原本声称其帐号被盗
"Originally claimed his account had been hacked,
辞职声明中承认与一名15岁女孩
"Resignation statement admits inappropriate correspondence
有不正当通讯
"With a 15-year-old girl."
发鸡巴照片叫通讯了吗
So tweeting dick photos is correspondence now, is it?
其辞职导致斯坦顿福德和赫舍姆选区
"Departure triggers a by-election in his Stentonford
需要进行补选
and Hersham constituency."
你可以说格莱德维尔的段子了
Well, you get to use the Gladwell stuff.
调到独白最前面
Bump it all up to the top of the monologue.
有人看到詹米了吗
Anyone seen Jamie?
瑞秋吗
Rach?
你不能再给我打电话了
You really shouldn't be calling me any more.
你得自己想清楚
You need to sort yourself out.
我想好了
I am.
专注于沃多  你干得不错
Focus on Waldo, that's going well for you.
但它不是
But it is not...
他红了  詹米
He's a hit, Jamie.
是他  不是我  是他
"He". Not me, "He".
做好你的节目
Just do your show.
我会的  我是说  亲爱的  如果你能
I will. I mean, hon, if you'd just...
詹米
Jamie?
詹米  快点
Jamie, hurry up.
对斯坦顿福德和赫舍姆选区你有什么了解
What do you know about Stentonford and Hersham?
保守党的支持区
Safe Tory seat.
所以现实点说  我知道机会不大  但是
So, realistically, I know there's not much of a chance, but...
所以对你来说就是一块垫脚石吗
So, it's a stepping stone for you?
是的
Yes.
当然  出了这道门我不会这么说
Obviously, I wouldn't say that outside of this room,
但你们要我坦诚以对
but, well, you want me to be honest.
那就没必要装相了
There's no point in pretending.
你过去有没有什么会对你不利的事
Is there anything in your past that might conceivably cause problems?
没有
No.
除了
Except...
我在1999年到2003年间
I did commit a series of murders in
在哈德斯菲尔德杀了几个人
Huddersfield between 1999 and 2003.
不过除了这个
But apart from that...
谢谢  格温多林
Well, thank you, Gwendolyn.
麻烦你从那个门出去
If you could leave via that door.
那个门吗
Oh, that door?
我们不想让候选人见面
We like to keep the candidates separate.
是的  好的
Right, yes.
白痴  白痴
Idiot. Idiot!
丢人的宠物美容大师  邻里的大傻瓜
Shamed super groomer and all-round pillock of the community
杰森·格莱德维尔辞去国会议员一职
Jason Gladwell has resigned as an MP,
声称他无法维持其位置
saying he could no longer maintain his position.
这个位置  估计是蜷起身
That position, presumably, being hunched over
冲着学生妹狂撸
wanking madly at school kids.
格莱德维尔的一位朋友称
A pal of Gladwell said...
准备好了吗
You ready?
...那姑娘不是几岁
...how old the girl wasn't.
这种可笑的借口
That's the sort of feeble excuse
也就学生能接受"吞下去"
only a naive school kid would swallow,
估计他就是这个打算
which, presumably, was the idea.
总之  坏消息是他不光彩地辞职了
Anyway, the bad news is he's resigned in disgrace.
好消息是  他现在可以全身心投入
The good news is he's now free to pursue a full-time career
可耻的恋童癖产业了
in the disgraced paedophile industry.
就我而言  真不明白怎么会有人觉得惊讶...
Personally, I don't understand why anyone's surprised...
- 开头小改一下  - 怎么改
- Um, small change to the intro. - What?
没什么  康纳独白想用杰克逊的段子...
Nothing huge, Conor wanted the Jacko gag for the monologue, so...
那是我的
That was my bit.
你可以说大臣的段子
There is the Chancellor stuff, you could use that.
那是政治
Bit politics.
你能说好政治的
You can do politics.
我只会嘲弄
I do piss-taking.
好好做沃多吧
Go be Waldo.
遵命  长官
Yes, commander.
劳·凯利相信自己能飞
R Kelly believed he could fly,
迈克尔·杰克逊相信自己有个好医生
and Michael Jackson believed that his doctor was qualified...
吃葡萄不吐葡萄皮
Big ball blue bear bollocks.
现在有请
And now it's time for our final visit
深受大家喜爱
to the world of educational children's programming
偶尔爆个粗口
courtesy of everyone's favourite,
教育性儿童电视节目人物
and only occasionally inappropriate cool kids' TV character,
沃多
Waldo.
显然  某人的妈妈来了
Whose mum's in tonight, apparently.
沃多  这周山洞里的是谁
Waldo, who have you had in your cave this week?
康纳  这周我粉色大山洞里
Well, Conor, in my big pink cave this week
是前文化部部长连姆·门罗
I had former Minister for Culture Liam Monroe.
他挺帅的  对吧
Oh, he's quite handsome, isn't he?
我还想让他吹我呢
I was hoping he'd nosh me off!
想看看结果如何吗
Want to see how it panned out?
必须的
I think we should.
播放录像
Run VT!
(沃多瞧瞧看)
大家好
Hey, everybody!
又到了沃多时间
It's Waldo time!
太棒了
Cool! Cool!
沃多真棒
Waldo-rrific!
孩子们  这周我的嘉宾是门罗先生
Hey, kids, my guest this week is Mr Monroe.
你好  门罗先生
Hello, Mr Monroe.
你好  沃多
Hello, Waldo.
门罗先生是个政客
Mr Monroe is a politician.
(政客)
什么是政客  门罗先生
So, what is a politician, Mr Monroe?
政客就是
Well, a politician is someone
想让世界更好的人
who tries to make the world a fairer place.
就好像蝙蝠侠
Like Batman.
也不能这么说
Not exactly like Batman.
你打坏人吗
Do you beat people up?
不  我不打人
No, I don't beat people up.
那你就是个孬种了
Oh, you're a pussy then?
我不太清楚什么叫...
Well, I'm not sure I know exactly what...
你不知道什么叫孬种
You don't know what pussy is?
这是在开玩笑吧
OK, this is clearly some kind of joke.
抱歉  不说笑了  我们继续
No joke, sorry, let's move on.
还是好朋友
Friends again?
你好  伙计  节目太棒了
Oh, hello, mate, great show.
干得好
Well done, really good.
我们带他过去
So, we'll bring him over.
你去叫他  我来解释...
You go and get him, I'll explain about...
他走过...
Now, he comes across...
詹米
Jamie!
有什么事吗  塔辛姆小姐
What you want, Miss Tamsin?
我身后那个跟杰克·奈皮尔说话的眼镜男
Behind me, man in glasses talking to Jack Napier.
我很怕杰克
Jack freaks me out.
我也是
Yeah, ditto,
但他是老板  跟他说话的是个大人物
but he owns the company and the man he's with is important
那人找你
and wants to talk to you.
他是台里来的
He's from the channel.
去吧
Go on.
说真的  我的意思是...
Honestly, all I'm saying...
不  我的意思是他是个好人...
No, all I'm saying is he's a terrific guy...
吉姆  这位是詹米  詹米  这位是吉姆
Jim, Jamie, Jamie, Jim.
你好吗
How do you do?
吉姆  杰克  詹姆斯
Jim, Jack, James.
我是詹米
Jamie.
吉姆刚还说起沃多
Jim was just talking about Waldo.
连姆·门罗提出投诉了
Yeah. Liam Monroe has lodged a complaint.
小题大做
Toys out the pram.
这是...
And that's...?
好宣传
Good press.
这年头想有所突破太难了
It's so tough to get a breakthrough these days,
一旦能做到  就棒极了
but when it does, well, it's just fantastic.
沃多惹毛门罗那段  真是太精彩了
It's fantastic the way Waldo puts the piss up Monroe.
那些笨蛋  都是蠢货  都是...
You know, all those twats, it's punk, it's... it's...
杰克
Jack?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
沃多在推特上火了  人气爆棚啊
Well, Twitter can't get enough of Waldo, loves him.
我知道这节目明年才继续
Look, I know the show's coming back again next year,
但我们想多让沃多出境
but we want to see more of Waldo.
他们想做一个试播集
They want to do a pilot.
沃多的试播集
A Waldo pilot?
对  你觉得怎么样
Yeah. I mean, how does that sound?
我觉得很棒
Yeah. Sounds good.
酷毙了  太他妈酷了
Sounds stormin' Norman, fucking stormin'.
给他们点颜色瞧瞧
Going to give it to 'em.
(恭喜  您入选了  请明早致电我办公室  希拉·汤普森)
但是  没有沃多我们什么都做不了
But look, we can't do sketches without Waldo.
这是个沃多的试播集  沃多秀
It's a Waldo pilot, it's a Waldo show,
整个节目就围绕着沃多
it's got to be Waldo, Waldo, Waldo.
现实点说  我们没有经费做别的动画了
Realistically, there isn't the budget for other animations.
我是说真人造型  我做其他人物
I mean live action, other characters I can do.
棕色骑士(出自《克利夫兰秀》)怎么样
What about the Brown Knight?
那个没用的骑士吗
What, the crap crusader?
棕色骑士可以再考虑
We can look into the Brown Knight.
但现在  我们先想些沃多的点子
But right now let's find more Waldo ideas.
问题是  我们约的嘉宾都会了解情况
The problem is, any guests we book will be in on it.
他们知道沃多爱胡闹
They know that Waldo's a joke,
这就没法出其不意了
the surprise is gone.
这点我们要斟酌一下
So, we think round that.
孩子们  现在是沃多时间
Hey, boys and girls! It's Waldo time!
他真棒  是不是
He's awesome, isn't he?
你看看  不仅家喻户晓
I mean, look, sod name in lights,
你都成软件了  兄弟
you're an app now, my brother.
怎么样  莎拉
All right, Sara?
智囊团进展如何  有好点子不
How's the think tanking going, good shit?
不错  不错  有进展了
Um, yeah, yeah, we're making headway.
很好
Good.
我们的朋友门罗又上新闻了
I see our friend Monroe is in the news again,
宣布参加斯坦顿福德补选
running in the Stentonford by-election.
我们该让沃多插一手
We should get Waldo down there.
这主意还真不错
Hey, that's not a bad idea, actually.
我们弄个货车  侧面屏幕放沃多的图像
We get a van with a screen with the image of Waldo on the side.
有意思
Like it.
然后  等门罗跟人寒暄的时候
And then, when Monroe's doing a meet and greet,
我们就出现  惹毛他
we just turn up and just get under his skin.
太妙了  我喜欢
I love that, I love it.
我们戏弄过门罗了
We've done Monroe.
可那次相当精彩
But it was a great bit.
我不是傻子  也没聪明到可以玩政治
I'm not dumb or clever enough to be political...
我们让沃多也参加补选怎么样
Why don't we get Waldo to stand for the by-election?
让人们投票给他
Get people to vote for him?
他连个人都不是
He's not real.
但之前也有人以虚构身份参选过
But people have stood as fictional characters before.
你以为"嚎叫的上帝萨奇(英国音乐家)"是他的真名吗
Do you think Screaming Lord Sutch was his real name?
我们在选票上注明"俗称沃多"就行了
We just put "Commonly known as" on the ballot.
没人会真的投票给他  投票不是重点
No-one's actually going to vote for him, that's not the point.
重点是  我们可以凑热闹  可以参与计票
The point is, we get to hang around, we're there for the count.
莎拉  快写上去吧
Well, go on then, Sara, whack it up there.
(重制推特  奥斯卡红毯秀  桥牌恶搞  福尔摩斯二世  投票给沃多)
(连姆·门罗  保守党)
他在和几对母子讲话
He's with a mum and baby group.
准备直播  五  四  三  二
OK. Going live in five, four, three, two...
非常感谢大家今天上午能来
Thank you so much for joining me this morning.
让我学到不少东西
It's been incredibly informative
我觉得我们应该
and I think we should
给孩子们来点掌声
have a little round of applause for the children,
他们表现非常棒
who were fantastic.
内奥米  谢谢你
Thank you, Naomi.
谢谢大家
Thank you for your time.
大家好  我是沃多
Hey, it's me Waldo.
伙计  我喜欢你的运动鞋
Oh. I like your trainers, man!
我自己也想穿运动鞋
I'd wear trainers myself
可我穿不了  因为没有脚
but I can't cos I haven't got feet.
只有一对桩子腿
I've got stumps.
他出来了
He's out.
门罗先生  门罗先生
Hey, Mr Monroe! Mr Monroe.
你结识哪个妈妈了吗
Hey! Did you get off with any of the mums?
她们哺乳时你眼睛看哪呢
Where'd you look while they were breastfeeding?
她们大奶子里全是奶水  门罗先生
They got big milky tits, Mr Monroe!
他说的
He said it!
门罗先生  别走呀
Mr Monroe, don't walk away from me!
- 我被冷落了  - 连姆  我真抱歉
- Hey, I'm being snubbed!  - I'm sorry about this, Liam.
别当我不存在  别进车子里去
Hey, don't ignore me. Don't just get in your car.
那可是个危险场所  瞧瞧它
It's a death trap anyway, look at it!
去查一下车里那些白痴的资料
Let's find out what we can about the idiot inside that thing.
是
Sure.
门罗先生  等等
Mr. Monroe. Oi!
你好  这里是斯坦顿福德工党
Stentonford Labour Party.
你可以选择页面风格
Right, you've got a choice of styles,
从那里面选择一个就行  再在这里输入姓名
so just choose one from there. Then you put your name in there.
这简直和Moonpig(销售贺卡的网站)如出一辙
This is like bloody Moonpig.
别把免费邮箱发爆了
Don't knock the free mail out.
连姆·门罗肯定不会用这么幼稚的传单软件
Bet Liam Monroe doesn't use some Fisher-Price leaflet app.
他又用不着
He doesn't have to.
今天是斯坦顿福德和赫舍姆选区竞选的首日
Day one of the campaign in Stentonford and Hersham,
保守党希望连姆·门罗能迎来开门红
and Tory hopeful Liam Monroe hits the ground running.
我一直关心执照费的问题
The licence fee is something that's very close to my heart...
门罗先生  请看看我啊  门罗先生
Mr. Monroe, ey! Oh, oh, oh! Look at me Mr. Monroe, please!
我在这儿  我在这儿
Hey, over here! Hey, over here...
看过来啊  门罗先生
Look over here, Mr. Monroe...
保守党一直...
The Conservative Party have been, er...
一直支持降低执照费
have been arguing for a reduction of the licence fee for...
大家早上好
Good morning, everybody.
你说什么
Pardon?
抱歉  你说什么
I beg your pardon.
抱歉  这里有点吵
I'm sorry. It's rather loud.
我们一直支持进一步降低执照费用
We have argued for a further reduction in the licence fee...
那个推婴儿车的妈妈  把她拉进来
Mum with a pushchair, drag her into it.
那位推婴儿车的妈妈
Hey, you. Mum with the pushchair.
就是你  问问门罗先生为什么不理我
Yeah, you. Ask Mr. Monroe why he's ignoring me.
你为什么不理沃多
Why are you ignoring Waldo?
门罗先生  沃多怎么惹到你了
Mr. Monroe, what's Waldo done to you?
我们应该趁这事闹开之前赶快离开
We should probably just shift before this turns stupid.
我才不会躲一个卡通人物呢
I'm not walking away from a cartoon.
我没不理你啊
I'm not ignoring you.
你就是没理我  真伤心
Yeah, you were, you upset me.
你让沃多伤心了
You made Waldo sad.
显然  你的伤心让我悲痛万分
Well, obviously, I'm absolutely devastated that you're upset...
让他插句话
Let him get a word in.
我没有不理"你"  因为"你"根本就不存在
I'm not ignoring you because there is no you.
你只是由喜剧演员配音的动画形象而已
You are an image voiced by a comedian...
准确的说  是所谓的喜剧演员
an alleged comedian, more accurately.
如果我不是真的  你为什么还跟他说话
If I'm not real, why you talking to him?
我说的"他"也就是我  白痴
And by "Him" I mean me, knobber!
我没必要一个卡通人物交谈啊
There's no point in attempting to converse with a cartoon.
是"交谈"啊  老爷
Ooh, "converse", Your Lordship!
你华丽的辞藻都让我勃起了
Thy flowery language doth give me a right throbbing bone-on!
结束了
Finished.
喝一杯吗
Drink?
我得处理一些邮件
I've got e-mails.
你知道她是格温多林·哈里斯吧
You know that's Gwendolyn Harris?
工党的候选人
The Labour candidate.
你看过我给你的背景资料吗
Did you read my background doc?
看了
Yes.
今晚看吧  一个人看
Why don't you read it tonight? Alone.
我大概九点左右过来  你先吃好早饭
I'll swing by about nine, so have your breakfast first...
你是我爸爸吗
Are you my dad?
显然不是  明天见
Apparently not. See you tomorrow.
沃多熊逼得门罗哑口无言
...Waldo the bear left Monroe in stunned silence.
活泼的沃多以其
The colourful Waldo launched
一贯的张扬和嘲弄风格开始了竞选之旅
his own campaign in typically loud and crowd-pleasing style...
你还真胆大啊  我们认识吗
Someone's bold? Do I know you?
就这样对待选民啊
Nice way to greet a voter...
抱歉  我以为你是
Sorry, I thought you were...
确切地说  我是你的对手
Actually, I'm more of a rival.
门罗先生  你为什么不理我  门罗先生
Hey, Mr. Monroe, Mr. Monroe, why are you ignoring me, Mr. Monroe?
模仿地很像啊
You're good at that!
因为我就是啊
Because I am that.
什么  你就是那东西
What? You're that thing?
沃多不是东西  而是一只熊
Waldo's not a thing, he's a bear.
连姆·门罗叫的更难听
Liam Monroe calls him worse.
顺便说一句干得漂亮
Nice work there, by the way.
不过是整他的玩笑罢了
Yeah, well. It's dick jokes at his expense basically.
再来一杯吗
Another one?
好啊  再喝一杯
OK. One.
你说得就好像
The way you describe it,
你只是为了拍个宣传片
it's like you're doing this for a showreel...
不是的
No...
这地方就是喜剧里的龙套角色
Like this place is the equivalent of a walk-on in a sketch show...
但政党领袖又必须出席
..But your party leader has to show up
因为这是个中期什么的...
because it's a...mid-thing...
中期补选
Midterm by-election.
故弄玄虚
Terminology tits.
你就是个小孩
You are 12!
因为领导人来了
So because leaderballs is there,
就像给瑞奇·热维斯(英国著名演员)的喜剧跑龙套
suddenly it's walk-on in a Ricky Gervais sketch show
是曝光的好机会
so it's good exposure.
你不会赢的  你知道你不会赢
You're not going to win, you know you're not going to win...
别说了
Come on.
你怎么样都不会赢
You're not going to win though.
没错
Of course not.
那为什么不说实话
So, why not be honest?
反正你们这些混蛋也不为我投票
Say, "You arseholes aren't going to vote for me,
我就说说我的想法吧
"So here's what I think anyway."
这行不通
It doesn't work like that.
什么都行不通  一切都是瞎扯
Nothing does. That's right. Everything's bullest.
你干得有声有色居然这么大怨气
You're angry, for someone who's doing well.
我给一只蓝熊配音
I'm the voice of a blue bear...
如果这也叫有声有色  那我们都完了
if that's, "Doing well," then we are doomed!
我看不见
I can't see!
等等  开关有点问题
Hang on, there's a thing.
你养了只狐狸  还是活得像14岁孩子
Have you had a fox in here or do you live like a 14-year-old?
别那么激动  我不会睡这上面的
Well, don't get too excited, I'm not sleeping in it.
见鬼  你说真的
Shit, really?
你真美
You're amazing.
什么
Sorry?
你真美
You're amazing?
谢谢
Oh, thank you!
怎么了
What's up?
没事
Nothing.
真的没事
Are you sure?
只不过
It's just...
我最近心情不太好
I haven't been happy in a while...
而这感觉很棒
And this is good, you know?
能给我你的号码吗
Can I...have your number?
好
Yes!
(连姆·门罗被卡通人物骚扰)
今早去哪
Where's our mark this morning?
我们压马路去
We're out on the road.
不错嘛
Ooh...bien sur.
大家好  我是门罗先生
Oh, hello, I'm Mr.Monroe.
为我投票  继续糟糕
Vote for me and keep things shitty.
(致格温多林  美女  抱歉这么叫你  你怎么样)
投票给沃多  投票给沃多
Vote Waldo! Vote Waldo!
你说得没错  坚挺的保守党
You're right. Strong Tory.
我警告过你
I warned you.
邻居相隔这么远  肯定是门罗的地盘
You know you're on Monroe turf when they live so far apart.
我要投票给沃多
I'm voting Waldo!
昨晚我碰到了沃多
I met Waldo last night.
詹米  那个扮演他的人
Jamie, the guy who plays him.
他很幽默
He's fun.
幽默
Fun?
你跟他说了我们竞选的事吗
Did you tell him anything about our campaign?
不算说了
Not really.
是不算  还是没有
Not really or no?
不算吧
Er, not really.
他没关系
Look, he's OK.
他是个喜剧演员
He's a comedian...
他现在嘲笑门罗  下一个就是你
he's mocking Monroe now, it'll be you next.
他只会说脏话和黄段子
His act is all f-this and penis jokes.
但...
But...
别再跟他见面
Don't see him again.
明天上霍斯汀节目前  都没活儿了
OK. Job done till the Husting tomorrow.
几个传媒学生在做类似《质询时间》的节目
Some media students doing a Question Time type thing.
他们也请了沃多
They've asked Waldo to join the panel.
得了吧  上《质询时间》简直是恶梦
Oh, come on. It's my nightmare, going on Question Time.
一些学生罢了  你行的
It's students, you'll walk it.
- 我回答不了正经的问题  - 没人让你那么做
- I can't answer serious questions... - No-one wants you to!
别紧张  你就是开心果
You're the comic relief, lighten up.
看看吧  你们会有很多发现
Erm, just have a look. I'm sure you'll find lots in there...
你们还有什么想谈的问题吗
Are there any particular issues that you're concerned about at all?
我以为我们要...
I thought we were going to...?
抱歉  我今天很忙
Sorry, I've had a tough day...
好吧  喝一杯都来不及吗
Right. Not even one?
抱歉
Sorry.
那明天呢
Well, what about tomorrow?
我不能  竞选期间我不能跟你见面
Look, I can't, when this is happening, I can't see you.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
他们以为这很像《质询时间》吗
Do they think that looks like Question Time?
是的  看起来很政治化
Yeah. It looks politicsy.
你看那主持人
Check the host.
想扮丁博比(英国著名政治评论员)呢
Jailbait Dimbleby.
谈到吸毒的人  我们应该心怀同情
When it comes to addiction and addicts, we should sympathise,
但不能纵容
but we shouldn't patronise.
吸毒是一种自愿行为  为了体验快感
You know, serious drug use is a criminal offence,
而做出的犯罪行为
that is committed voluntarily and for pleasure...
我也不想这么说  可这是事实
Look, I'm sorry, these are the facts.
沃多  你觉得呢
Waldo, what do you think?
门罗先生  你是瘾君子吗
Mr Monroe, are you addicted?
我不是
No.
不好意思  我说错了  你是伪君子吗
Sorry, I mean, are you a dickhead?
我觉得我们得扪心自问
I think we have to ask ourselves...
我觉得我们得扪心自问  这有何意义
I think we have to ask ourselves, what is this for?
我们为什么要浪费时间
And why do we waste our time
跟这种动画人物胡闹呢
with animated trivialities like him?
为什么
I mean why?
为什么呢  为什么呢
Why? I mean why?
这是为什么呢
I mean why? I mean why?
为什么呢  为什么呢
这就是个闹着玩的笑话
This is just the kind of thing... rather than see you laugh...
他们在笑你  傻小子
They laugh at you, Limbo.
你们是在笑一个不肯好好说话
You laugh, you're laughing at someone who won't engage.
害怕正面对话  躲在卡通人物的后面的人
Who is scared to engage, who hides behind a children's cartoon.
笨蛋  你说谁是卡通人物
Who you calling a kiddy toon, fool?
我是在说詹姆斯·绍特
I'm...I'm...I'm speaking about James Salter.
- 别慌  - 那是你的名字  对吧
- Don't worry about it. - That's your name, isn't it?
詹姆斯·绍特  就是在背后操纵的人
James Salter, this is the man who's behind all this.
他今年33岁
He's 33 years old,
寥寥几个字就能概括他的职业经历
a man whose career can be summed up surprisingly quickly.
六年前  你还在一个小剧团
You were in a sketch troupe
当时那个剧团办得还算可以
that enjoyed minor success about six years ago,
剧团其他人都展翅高飞了
and the others moved on to better things,
而你的主要成似乎就只有
but your main achievement seems to have been
在一则高息个人贷款广告里
playing the part of a corn on the cob
扮演一根玉米棒子
in a high-interest personal loan commercial.
我发现你对此很低调啊
I notice you keep that pretty quiet.
而现在  你操纵这个类似泰迪熊的东西
And now of course operating this sort of teddy bear thing.
这活儿太简单了  谁都能干
Which by the way is easier than it looks. Anyone could do it.
就是这么回事
See, this is...this is the thing.
他做的事很简单
It's easy, what he does.
他嘲弄别人
He mocks.
当他想不出正经笑话时
And when he can't think of an authentic joke,
这是常有的情况  他就靠骂人取宠
which is actually quite often, he just swears.
我认为  这样一个傀儡出现在辩论中
I think that this puppet's inclusion on this panel
贬低了这场辩论
debases the process of debate,
扼杀了一切有意义的讨论
and smothers any meaningful discussion of the issues.
所以  回到我一开始的问题
So I return to my original question,
这真的是我们的目的吗
is that really what this is for?
他给不了什么  也说不出什么有意义的话
He has nothing to offer and he has nothing to say.
我说得对吗
Prove me wrong. Hm?
说话啊  沃多
Speak, Waldo.
请说  来吧  说啊
Please. Come on. Speak up.
大家看见了吧  什么都没有
There you see, nothing.
你丫玩蛋去
Oh, go fuck yourself.
又在骂人了
It's more swearing.
你就是个笑柄
You're a joke.
你还没我有人样
You look less human than I do
而我是个有蓝色鸡巴的假熊
and I'm a made-up bear with a turquoise cock.
你呢  不过是个新瓶装旧酒的老顽固
What are you? You're just an old attitude with new hair.
看我懒得鸟你  你就自以为高贵啦
Assuming you're my superior because I'm not taking you seriously?
根本没人鸟你  所以才没人投票
No-one takes you seriously, that's why no-one votes.
大多数人都投票
The vast majority do vote.
胡扯
It's bullshit.
闹够了吧
Surely this is enough?
你自以为该受尊重
You think you deserve respect.
这是礼貌
Just common courtesy.
就因为你读过公学
Because you went to public school
就觉得什么都是应当的
and believed you were entitled to everything.
也许我们该回到
Perhaps we could get back...
你这是无理取闹
Ad hominem nonsense...
格温多林·哈里斯
Gwendolyn Harris...
必须有所改变  没人相信你们
Something's got to change. No-one trusts you lot
因为大家都知道
cos they know
你们对自身以外的事都毫不在意
you don't give a shit about anything outside your bubble.
那个给小孩露鸟的格莱德维尔呢
What about your mate Gladwell, the kiddy-flasher?
你们认识二十年了
You knew him for 20 years,
你不知道他是怎样的人吗
did you not know what he was like?
当然不知道
No, of course not.
对啊  因为你们都在装样子  狡诈而做作
Yeah, cos you're all just front, like him, sly and pretending,
如此看来你们都一样
and in that way you're all the same.
格温多林·哈里斯  政治都是浪费时间吗
Gwendolyn Harris, is all of politics a waste of time?
我当然不这么认为
Well, of course I think no...
闭嘴吧  你更差劲
Oh, shut up, you're worse!
真的  她比他还虚伪
Seriously, she's faker than him.
这次我不得不认同连姆·门罗的看法
For once I agree with Liam Monroe in that
这样说下去毫无用途
this really doesn't get us anywhere and
所以没必要继续这种...
there's no point in us continuing...
如果我们不能进行真正意义上的辩论
..If we can't have anything resembling a deba...
她就是来做宣传的
She's here to build a showreel.
不是开玩笑  就是这么回事
I'm not kidding, that's literally it.
她知道她赢不了
Knows she's not going to win.
这就是为积累经验  上电视
This is all experience, to herself get on telly.
与他相比  她更不在乎这里的任何人
She actually gives less of a shit about anyone round here than he does,
因为他回头还得代表你们的利益
because he'll actually have to represent you.
我说错了吗
Am I wrong?
职业政客
A career politician.
比我还要虚假的人
Someone else less real than me,
我还能做这个呢
and I can do this.
我能说两句吗
Can I just make a couple of points?
闭嘴吧  你个石头蛋
Oh, shut up, you pebble.
你不是问意义何在吗  门罗先生
What is this for? That's what you wanted to know, Mr Monroe.
事实就是  因为你
And the truth is,
我们都不知道这还有什么意义
none of us know any more, thanks to you.
你有什么意义  你有什么意义
What are you for? What are you for?
谢谢  晚安
Thank you and goodnight.
詹米
Jamie.
Jamie?
杰克来了  他要见我们
Jack's here. He wants to see us.
这你躲不开
You can't avoid it.
穿衣服吧  他在外面跟我们碰头
Get dressed, he'll meet us outside.
不说那些认为他无趣的批评
And yet accusations of vapidity aside,
这些话显然触动了人们的神经
it's clearly tapped a nerve.
仅三天  沃多已在网络疯传
in just three days, Waldo has gone viral.
他大发脾气的视频
The video of his clash
在YouTube上已经浏览了超过百万次
has already been viewed over a million times on YouTube.
Facebook上甚至有团体呼吁沃多
There are Facebook groups calling on Waldo
建立国家党派
to form a national party.
你就是个笑柄
You're a joke.
你还没我有人样
You look less human than I do
而我是个有蓝色鸡巴的假熊
and I'm a made-up bear with 'a turquoise...
你呢
What are you?
不过是个新瓶装旧酒的老顽固
You're just an old attitude with new hair.
看我懒得鸟你  你就自以为高贵啦
Assuming you're my superior because I'm not taking you seriously.
根本没人鸟你
No-one takes you seriously.
瞧啊  时下的风云人物
Oh, look, here he is the man of the moment!
成为网络红人什么感觉啊
How does it feel to be a phenomenon?
吓傻了
Shitifying.
到处是你啊
You are everywhere, my son.
推特  新闻  你看到民意调查了吗
Twitter, the news... Have you seen the poll?
你已经排第三了
You're in third place, mate.
你超过了那个自由民主党的家伙
You overtook that Lib Dem prick...
他屁都不是
Yeah, well, he's a glass of water.
这是个大好机会  詹米
This is an opportunity, Jamie.
他知道我的名字了
He knows my name now.
我们可以大展拳脚
We could really do something here.
大家都对现状不满
You know, everyone's pissed with the status quo.
沃多发出了呐喊
And Waldo gives that a voice.
沃多是只熊  蓝色的熊
Waldo's a bear. A blue bear.
告诉他  塔辛
Tell him, Tams.
我们受邀参加《舆论》
We've been asked on Consensus.
跟菲利普·科雷一对一进行十分钟采访
It's a ten-minute one-to-one interview with Phillip Crane.
斗犬科雷吗
Pitbull Crane?
毒舌对名嘴
Big guns for big guns.
喂  我不是政客
Hello? I'm not a politician, OK?
我也不想做政客
I don't want to be a politician.
我们知道你讨厌政治
We know that you hate politics.
我不恨政治  我只是不感兴趣
I don't hate them, I'm just not interested in them.
你不非得感兴趣
You don't need to be interested in them.
你只要做好沃多就行
You just need to be Waldo.
要是科雷问了什么刁蛮的问题  我答不上来
And when Crane asks something tricky and I look stupid
就会丢人现眼了
because I don't know how to answer?
你不会答不上来的
You'll know the answer.
因为你还有个制作人呢
Because you have a producer.
我可以告诉你该说什么
Look, I can tell you what to say.
我可以实时谷歌  查资料  转述
I can live Google any facts, give you stats, quotes,
所有你需要的东西
whatever else you need.
所以那些实打实的东西有保障
So you've got a safety net for the concrete stuff
再就是沃多了  你梦里都能做好
and the rest is Waldo and you can do that in your sleep.
你会完爆科雷的
You'll piss all over Crane.
他会知道我有团队帮忙  他会看到的
He'll know there's a team around me, he'll see it.
那才好呢  我希望他都给拍下来
Yeah good. I hope he does. I hope he points a camera at it.
所有议员都有团队
All the other MPs have got teams,
我们不对此做隐瞒
we're just more honest about it.
怎么样  好不好
Now come on. What d'you say? Eh?
詹米  詹米
Jamie! Jamie!
我为什么要这么做
Why would I want to do this?
这个世界都感到厌烦  你可以激起他们的兴趣
Look, the world is knackered and you can do something about it.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're on about.
沃多能吸引年轻人的注意
Waldo has got the attention of the young,
而年轻人什么都不在乎
and the young don't give a shit about anything
就知道运动鞋和盗版片
except trainers and pirating films.
你还有其他关于年轻人的大理论吗
Do you have any other astounding theories about young people?
我还真是有
Yeah, yeah I do actually.
他们关心沃多
Look, they care about Waldo.
他们会为沃多投票的
They'll vote for Waldo.
那段视频火起来是有原因的
The video was a hit for a reason.
那段视频就是丢人  我觉得丢人
The video's embarrassing. I'm embarrassed by it.
我当时发火了  我说话都不清楚
I was lashing out. I wasn't even articulate...
- 没关系的  - 也不搞笑  那更糟
- Doesn't matter. - Or funny, which is almost worse.
这是个好基础
We can build on that.
沃多不是真的
Waldo's not real.
没错  这正是最深入人心的部分
Exactly! That's what you said that really hit home.
他不是真的
He's not real,
但他比其他人更加真实
but he's realer than all the others.
他毫无立场
He doesn't stand for anything.
那他也不装作有立场
Yeah, well, at least he doesn't pretend to.
我们不需要政客
Look we...we don't need politicians,
我们都有iPhone和电脑  对不对
we've all got iPhones and computers, right?
任何需要作出的决定
So any decision that has to be made,
政策  都可以摆到网上
any policy, we just put it online.
让人民去投票  支持还是反对
Let the people vote thumbs up, thumbs down,
少数服从多数
the majority wins.
这才是民主呢  这才真的叫民主
That's a democracy. That's a... that's an actual democracy.
YouTube也民主
So's YouTube
但不知道你看到没
and I don't know if you've seen it
最受欢迎的视频
but the most popular video
是只狗用屁声模仿《快乐时光》主题曲
is a dog farting the theme tune to Happy Days.
今天最受欢迎的是沃多
Well, today it's Waldo.
不  还是那只狗
No. It's still the dog.
你想想如果我们把政客都赶下台
Listen, can you imagine all the things we can change
我们能做出多少改变啊
if we fuck the politicians out the equation?
我要说的都说了  现在我要关门了
I've said what I've said and now I'm shutting this door.
你知道沃多是谁的吗
Do you know who owns Waldo?
是我的
I do, I own the rights.
他是我创造的形象
He's my character.
对  你为我的节目创造的
Yeah, written for my show.
你不敢更上一层楼
You're too frightened to take to the next level.
好吧  我理解
Fine. I understand.
但你也给我滚边
But also, fuck off!
瞧着我飞吧
And watch me fly.
就算他是你的  你做不了沃多
You own Waldo, you can't be Waldo.
詹米  詹米  最近好吗
Eh, Jamie, Jamie, Jamie, what's 'appenin, eh?
我觉得差不多了
Pretty close, I'd say.
最近怎么样啊
What's happenin'? Ahh!
沃多真棒  好诶
Waldorific, yeah! Yeah!
这东西怎么又往左了
Why is it going off left again?
- 它怎么  - 因为...
- Why does it... - Because the...
我知道  我的...
I know! I've got my...
把你的拇指放进白色的东西里
Put your thumb in the white thing.
那儿吗  好的
I got that. In there? OK.
不是那么弄的
That's not how that works.
(舆论)
今晚首位嘉宾  是一个人或者说形象
First tonight, a figure or more accurately a character...
他在斯坦顿福德的补选中掀起风浪
who's been causing an upset in the Stentonford by-election.
与其他候选人不同  他不属于任何党派
Unlike the other candidates, he has no party affiliation.
甚至没有姓氏
He doesn't even have a surname.
他就是沃多  几周前
He is Waldo, a few weeks ago
只是一档喜剧节目中的角色
just a cult character in a comedy show.
而今  却成为抗议选举人的吉祥物
Today, an official mascot for protest voters.
投票给沃多
Vote Waldo.
卡通形象做事不按章法
Cartoons don't play by the rules
而沃多对其对手公然的蔑视
and Waldo's open disdain for his opponents
显然引起了共鸣
has clearly struck a chord.
沃多  作为底层人的吉祥物
Waldo, as a mascot for the disenfranchised,
你的做法不是令真正有效的异见不得重视吗
aren't you ultimately neutralizing seriously effective dissent?
能给科雷先生做个字幕吗
Can I have subtitles for Mr Crane, please?
你鼓励人们不要在意  实际上是很危险的
By encouraging people not to care, you're actively dangerous.
危险  你觉得民众不可信任吗
Dangerous? You think the public can't be trusted?
不
No.
你这不就是说他们是二货吗
Isn't that basically you calling them twats?
不
No, I...
傻逼吗
Bell-ends then?
你是来跟我探讨还是...
Did you come for a discussion or...
你就是个高级的木偶  居然这么自大  菲尔
You're snooty for a glorified Punch And Judy man, Phil.
你知道因为我来作客
You know you're gonna get your
你的收视率会达到几个月最高点
best ratings in months cos I'm here.
要想接近我今晚能给你拉来的收视
To even get close to the figures I'm gonna pull in for you tonight,
你得在直播间干一个虾肉三明治
you'd have to fuck a prawn sandwich live on air.
做个大虾冷盘
Make a nice prawn cocktail.
我们能不能探讨一些严肃的政治问题
Could we make a serious political point that is...
我有个蓝色的大"问题"
I've got one big blue point to make, fool.
- 想看看吗  - 天呐  谢谢
- Would you like to have a look at it? - Oh, God. Thank you.
今晚真棒  瞧啊  瞧
Great work tonight. Look at...Look at this, look at this.
这是沃多投票软件
It's The Waldo polling app.
这东西能定位你的位置
Now, this can pinpoint you with GPS
你一到投票点
so that when you're at a polling station,
它就骂一堆话  瞧
it unlocks loads of free shit, look.
多谢投票  二货
Thanks for voting, dickhead!
挺不错的吧
It's good, isn't it?
我们要见的是什么人
Who's this guy we're meeting?
我不知道
I dunno.
他是华盛顿来的  而且知道我的秘密号码
But he's from Washington and he's got my restricted number.
杰夫·卡特  局里的
Jeff Carter, from the agency.
我就直说了
And I'll leap right in.
我觉得你的沃多真是棒极了
I think what you're doing with Waldo is fascinating.
"局里的"
From "The agency"?
是的  听我说  沃多可以做最佳名义领袖
Yeah, listen. Waldo may be the perfect political figurehead.
沃多熊吗
Waldo The Bear.
人们喜欢这只熊  他是只熊是件好事
The bear, people like. The fact he's a bear is an assist.
好事
An assist?
有好处
It helps.
没错  人们看到一个政治人物
Right. You look at human politicians,
不知为什么就心生反感  对吧
you're instinctively like, "Brrrr", uncanny, right?
就像演黄片的女人
Like the girls in porn.
你就觉得她们不对劲  否则为什么做这个
You know something's wrong, cos why else are they doing it?
一般都是因为她们爸爸
It's usually daddy issues, eh?
就像政治  而沃多没这个问题
Just like politics. Waldo bypasses that.
你已经知道他是假的  就没有人的缺陷
You already know he's not real, so no personal flaws.
我就是人
I'm a person.
恕我直言  沃多比你大的多
With respect, Waldo's more than you.
他是个团队  而且你们并不遮掩  这很好
He's a team, and you're open about that, which is fantastic.
诚实很受欢迎
The honesty thing works.
人们不仅接受了沃多  而且喜欢他
Waldo is a construct people not just accept but embrace.
目前他抵触政治
At the moment he's anti-politics,
而这本身也是政治立场
which is a political stance itself, right?
但他能传达任何的政治理念
But he could deliver any brand of political content,
还能去除人的任何不良因素
minus the potential downsides of a human messenger.
在辩论中  你的团队可以搜索对方的每句话
In a debate, your team could Google every word the other guy says,
让沃多反驳他
then let Waldo hit him with debunk stats
还能跟上一句能在推特上疯传的话
and spit a Twitter-ready zinger into the next sentence.
他是最佳的打手
He's the perfect assassin.
我们赢不了的
We won't win, though.
你们太英国了
You guys are so British.
他当然赢不了
No, of course he won't win.
你们从一开始就是些粗俗段子
You started out too coarse off the bat.
你们提出的东西都是虚幻的
There's no substantial basis to what you offer,
那套虚无主义的"民主完蛋"论调
and the whole nihilist "Democracy sucks" thing,
是挺有话题性
yeah, is kind of wack-a-doo,
但如果有一条有意义的信息
but with a targeted, hopeful message,
这个我们可以提供
which we can provide,
既能激起底层人的热情又不吓坏中产阶级
energising the disenfranchised without spooking the middle
借助你们的新平台
via your new platform...
这就是全球性的政治娱乐产品
You got a global political-entertainment product
而且人们会想购买
people actually want.
你们可以向全球发展
You could roll this out worldwide.
就像品客薯片
Like Pringles.
是啊
Absolutely.
的确挺有趣的
It's, er... It's interesting stuff though.
等你们折腾够了斯坦顿福德
When you're done with Stentonford,
或许南美还有机会
there may be an opportunity in South America.
你会说西班牙语吗
Se puede hablar espanol?
在马德里生活了三年呢
Vivi en Madrid tres anos.
太好了
Excelente.
(投票给格温多林·哈里斯)
(格温强颜欢笑  哈里斯受羞辱)
怎么了
What?
他不来了
He's not coming.
他可是政党领袖啊
But he's the party leader!
影响太差了
It's too toxic.
与此同时  格温多林·哈里斯的支持率在减小
Meanwhile, as support for Gwendolyn Harris appears to be dwindling,
而工党否认党派对这位年轻的候选人失去了信心
Labour denies the party is losing faith in their young candidate.
而哈里斯小姐几乎整日在党总部忙于
But Miss Harris spent most of the day locked in crisis talks
应对危机
at party headqu...
在斯坦顿福德补选中
In the Stentonford by-election,
卡通熊沃多继续...
Waldo the cartoon bear continues...
你昨天看到格温多林·哈里斯了吗
Did you see Gwendolyn Harris yesterday?
就像是中毒了似的
She looks like she's been poisoned.
因为他会超过她
Because he's gonna overtake her.
我们还是遥遥领先
We're still way ahead.
如果那东西成了主要对手
If that thing is the main opposition
真是给整个系统丢脸
then the whole system looks absurd.
极可能就是这样
Which it may well be.
但系统还是建了这些路
But it built these roads.
进来吧  罗伊
Just come in, Roy.
很抱歉
I'm sorry, OK?
我不该那么跟你说话
It was wrong to speak to you like that and...
竞选结束后  我会给你打电话的
After the campaign, I would've called you.
竞选结束后
After the campaign!
你这样只是让门罗更占优势了
All you've done is strengthen Monroe.
你反正也不会赢
You won't win either,
但我至少还想代表...
but I was at least attempting to represent...
我也不知道是什么  但绝不是"都是瞎扯"
Well I don't know! Not just "Bollocks to everything".
如果你真想推行革命也算是厉害了
If you were preaching revolution, well that'd be something,
但你不是  因为那需要勇气和智慧
but you're not because that would require courage and a mindset.
你有什么
And what have you got?
你是什么
Who are you?
你有什么立场
What are you for?
早啊
Morning.
最后一击了
So, final push.
跟大家说有个软件
You remind everyone that's got the app
如果他们向朋友推荐
that if they recommend it to a friend
沃多就能得到顶帽子
it unlocks a little fez for Waldo.
我们到了
We're here.
各位请注意
Attention, shoppers.
我有要事相求  请过来
I'm here to ask you an important favour. Gather round.
过来  听我说
Come over here and listen.
别为我投票  我就是个侮辱
Don't vote for me. I'm an insult.
真的
Seriously.
投票给门罗或者哈里斯  或者独立党
Vote for Monroe or Harris or, I dunno, UKIP,
哪怕是那个自由民主党的家伙
or even that Lib Dem guy.
他是个二货
He's a prick!
真的  只有傻逼才会投票给我
Seriously, only an arsehole would actually vote for me.
你这是反讽吗
What is this? Irony?
你浪费一票都比投给我强
I'm worse than a wasted vote.
那人是哈里斯阵营的
He's from the Harris campaign.
我说真的  白痴  别投给我
I mean it, you idiots! Don't vote for me!
别投给我  别投给我
Don't vote for me! Don't vote for me!
别投给我
Don't vote for me!
Don't vmmmf!
闭嘴
Shut up.
不  别嘘他  他是对的
No. Don't boo him, he's right! He's right!
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
辞职
Resigning.
詹米
Jamie!
瞧啊  是我  我是沃多
Look! It's me, I'm Waldo.
这个人  不论他是谁  他是个英雄
This guy, whoever this guy is, he's a hero.
你们该冲沃多扔东西  他不是好东西
You should throw stuff at Waldo, he's bad bloody news.
他好玩
He's funny!
他不好玩
He's not.
别听他的  他是个女同性恋
Don't listen to that man, he's a lesbian. Ahh!
别忘了  投票开始了
So remember, the polls are open,
如果你们有我的软件
and if you've got my app,
可以解锁一些流行语或者小帽子什么的
you can unlock new stuff like catchphrases and a little hat 'n' that.
只有白痴才不会给我投票
Only an idiot wouldn't vote for me
质疑现状
so question the status quo!
杀掉他
Kill it! Kill it!
直击要害
Kick them where it hurts.
第一个打他的人有五百镑可拿
The first man to hit him gets 500 quid!
没错  打倒他
Yeah, that's right. Knock him down. Knock him down.
打扁他
Smash it!
好极了
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah...
我是斯坦顿福德和赫舍姆选区的
I, the undersigned, being the returning officer
署名选举监察人
for the Stentonford and Hersham constituency,
现在宣布每位候选人
hereby give notice that the total number of votes recorded for
所得选票总计如下
each candidate at the election is as follows.
西蒙·亚瑟·芬奇  自由民主党
Finch, Simon Arthur. Liberal Democrats.
2449票
2,449.
格温多林·乔迪·哈里斯  工党
Harris, Gwendolyn Jodie. Labour.
11237票
11,237.
连姆·乔治·丁尼生·门罗  保守党
Monroe, Liam George Tennyson. Conservative.
19161票
19,161.
沃多  无党派
Waldo, Independent.
16784票
16,784.
女士们先生们  请静静
Ladies...Ladies and gentlemen, please!
我宣布连姆·门罗
I declare that Liam Monroe
正式当选本选区下院议员
is duly elected member of Parliament for the constituency.
大家
Hey, hey! Everyone!
五百块给扔鞋的人
500 quid to anyone who can lob a shoe!
起来吧  来
Up you get, come on.
走吧
Come on!
走吧  出去
Come on. Out you go.
(改变)
(信念)
(希望)
(改变)
(未来)
(信念)